#### SAMSON ANAMI ONG'ONDA

samsonanami@gmail.com-0727 031 141/0717 084 613

P.O Box 20100-619, Nakuru, Kenya

#### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am an ambitious Computer Security and Forensic Specialist with zeal to scale heights in a view of technological advancements in the Information Technology and Computer fields. I have an appreciable knowledge of the ICT training role and am looking forward to expand my experience with a role that combines new builds and discoveries as well as my prior training. I am a team player with good communication skills and academic qualifications having a proven ability to improve efficiency in an organisation.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

ERP Consultant: July 2016 - December 2016

Mars Track ERP Solution – www.marstrackerp.com

Visions plaza, 5th floor of room 4, Mombasa Road-Nairobi

Responsibilities:

- Installation and customization of ERP System and reports design
- User Training and Training materials development
- Technical user support
- System Analysis and Design
- C# (Microsoft .NET Framework) programming
- Relational SQL database queries development and Crystal reports design

Technical Support Staff (Intern) – February 2015 – May 2015

Kenya Revenue Authority (KRA)-www.kra.go.ke

Times Tower Building, Haile Selassie Avenue – Nairobi Responsibilities:

- Working on Oracle-based Centralised Database System.
- Itax System Support for tax collection.
- Computer Maintenance; Hardware and Software
- Network Infrastructure Maintenance and Administration

## <u>Intern – February 2014 – June 2014</u>

Dedan Kimathi University of Technology - www.dkut.ac.ke

#### Skills Gained:

- System Development Life-Cycle in practise.
- Networking fundamentals
- Web Application Development
- Computer System Hardware and Software Maintenance

# **EDUCATION**

# Sep 5th 2017 - To date: MSc. IT Security and Audit

Kabarak University – Nakuru, Kenya

http://kabarak.ac.ke/

# Sep 2012 - Apr 2016: BSc. Information Technology

Dedan Kimathi University of Technology - Nyeri, Kenya

https://www.dkut.ac.ke/

## **Area of Expertise:**

System Analysis & Design | Network Management | Macroeconomics | Internet Application Programming | Application Programming (Java, Python & Php) | Marketing Management | Industrial Management | Data Structure and Algorithms | ICT Project planning

## **Technical Skills**

Microsoft Office | Microsoft Project | PHP | SQL | HTML5 | AngularJS | CSS | Bootstrap | Visual Basic | Java | Adobe Illustrator | Ajax | Android | MySQL | Yii Platform | Linux OS | Achievements:

- Working with a leading software development company in Kenya
- Working in a leading Government Organisation in ICT in Kenya

## Jan 2008 - Dec 2011: K.C.S.E Attained Grade - B+

Athinai Secondary School -Mogotio, Kenya.

## <u>Jan 1999 – Dec 2007: K.C.P.E- 336 Marks</u>

Kiamaina Primary School -Nakuru, Kenya.

## **Career Objective:**

- Eager to secure a position in an organization to apply my knowledge of Information Technology security along with my experience for growth of an organization.
- Looking for a job where I can utilize my educational qualifications in the field of computing and implement what I have gained through hard work and integrity

## **PERSONAL INTERESTS**

Travelling | Web Design | Computer networking | Graphics Design | Study ICT documentaries

# **REFERENCES**

Mrs. Marry Muchilwa

Deputy Registrar

P.O Box 297-40105

Maseno University (Homa-Bay Campus)

Tel: 0728 095 712

Email: mmuchilwa1@gmail.com

Mr. Hesbon Ojoji

**Technical Officer** 

P.O Box 270 Nakuru

Kenya Revenue Authority (KRA)

Tel: 0722 878 886

Email: ojojimajimbo@yahoo.com

More references are available on request.

Dr. Christopher M Maghanga, Ph.D

Senior Lecturer. Physics

Dean School of Computer Science &

**Bioinformatics** 

Kabara University

Tel: 0722 986 967

Email: <a href="mailto:cmaghanga@kabarak.ac.ke">cmaghanga@kabarak.ac.ke</a>